[♪♪♪]
H'yah!
[shattering]
[stamping]
[wind whooshing]
And I can expect
the remaining two chains
to be eliminated... when?
The final Prismatic Blades
are being hunted down
as we speak.
They'd better be.
So the Merge created
new monasteries in each realm?
That is my theory,
but there is so much
about the Merge
we still do not understand.
The idea
of traveling to realms
once nearly impossible to reach
is... invigorating.
I am surprised
you have not gone exploring.
As much as I enjoy
learning new things,
I enjoy them more
when I share them with you,
and you were not here.
I am here now.
We're, uh, not trying
to interrupt--
Oh, yes. Uh, of course.
Ninjago.
Nya! Kai!
So glad you're here!
Where's Wyldfyre?
Roby's not getting any better,
so she's staying back in--
[gasping]
Pixal?!
I can't believe it!
A pleasure
to see you again, Nya.
I am told
it has been some time.
Zane... you're...
huge.
I got swole for buffness.
[laughing] What?
A joke.
Nindroids do not build muscles
in that way.
Hence the humor.
Amusing!
Sora about told us
about the Forbidden Five
trying to unleash
some... big ancient dragon?
The Shatter Dragon of Chaos.
They need five
specific Prismatic Blades
to cut the dragon's
enchanted chains,
one blade for each chain.
They already have
three of them.
Then good thing
we've got this one.
If they need all the blades,
just destroy it.
Problem solved.
Just call me "the Solver."
One of them did shatter
in the tournament.
So maybe...
[sighing]
Let the Solver solve this.
So maybe the blade breaking
at the tournament
was some special situation?
Maybe magical?
The Dragonians can sense
where the blades are.
The Monastery is in danger.
Then let's take it with us
to find the last missing blade.
How do we find it?
We don't have
Dragonian trackers.
Huh, the Solver has no solve?
I...
[groaning] deserve that.
I believe Zane and I
can find a way
to track down the final blade.
♪ Lost in the unknown ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ We fight ♪
♪ Be a ninja
for what's right ♪
[♪♪♪]
Roby!
Looking so much better!
He's looking so much worse!
Where are we on a cure?
No solution
has been identified
in any of our Books of Lore.
[groaning]
Books of Lore are the worst!
Got it! Janus Melon Stew!
Roby is not suffering
from hunger.
The stew helps dragons
with the Wasting Sickness.
If it'll help big dragons,
imagine what it'll do
for tiny people...
maybe cure anything!
That logic is--
Perfect, I know.
Where can I get Janus Melons
around here?
They are rare,
but have been seen at the end
of the Jagged Tunnels,
an underground path
of almost always fatal dangers.
Cool. I'm gonna pop over there.
Your chances
of total destruction there
are near certain.
Nah. I'm good.
Can I borrow a ride, though?
You may use any vehicle
in the City's fleet.
Noice!
Something with racing stripes?
Kai taught me
all about racing stripes.
They make things go faster.
It is as if
you cannot hear my warning
about your impending destruction
if you pursue
this course of action.
My guy,
for Roby, I'd face, like,
a million
impending destructions.
Now, point me at something
that goes fast!
Do you remember
the exact location
of the Temple
of the Dragon Cores?
Of course.
I sense you are distracted.
No...
Well, my parents.
That cemetery.
How'd you know it was there?
I told you.
Everything Jay Walker learned
from his time
in the Administration
is now known by me.
And you'll really be able
to do what you said?
Bring them back?
Undoing the Merge
will release powers
more potent than anything
seen in these realms
since their creation...
the ability
to reshape reality itself.
Do you doubt me?
No, but I have
so many questions
about my parents.
During all those MergeQuakes
over the Crossroads,
I swear I saw--
What was that?
There.
[Arin] Friend of yours?
An unknown enemy.
Just because they're unknown
doesn't make them an enemy.
The unknown
is always the enemy.
Whoa, Mr. Cynical.
The unknown is usually
a potential friend.
Where'd he go?
[explosion]
[alerts beeping]
Our potential friend
is bombing us.
-[grunting]
-[yelping]
[explosion]
Yeah, okay, not a friend!
[explosions]
[grunting and groaning]
[blasting]
Ah!
[gasping]
So you seriously
have no idea who this is?
No.
And it doesn't bother you
that random people
just want to take you down?
Strength attracts challengers.
-Aah!
-[explosion]
[circuits shorting,
alerts beeping]
The drone will finish him off.
-[thudding]
-Aah!
Get rid of him!
Stop there! No closer!
[roaring]
[grunting]
[circuits shorting,
alerts beep]
[Arin yelping,
alerts beeping]
Aah!
This is going to hurt!
[exhaling] Ah...
Thank you!
You're from Riyu's tribe,
the Mountain Dragons, right?
You want me to go with you?
Sure!
[♪♪♪]
Riyu's family!
Hi, everyone!
[tiny roaring]
[squawking happily]
So good to see you again,
Matriarch!
The Matriarch
of the Mountain Tribe
welcomes your return,
Arin of the Crossroads.
I am Leaf Blade,
regent for the baby Matriarch.
I speak to outsiders
for Her Majesty
until she comes of age.
I owe you all big-time.
I was about to be a goner
when those dragons saved me.
[Matriarch squeaking]
The Matriarch says
it is the least we could do
for a hero like you.
"Hero"?
Me?
Of course.
You rescued
and befriended Riyu.
You battled
the Claws of Imperium
when they came for our tribe,
and you protected
the Baby Matriarch.
Your actions speak
of the person you are.
Well, I mean,
there was a whole team--
[Leaf Blade] The Matriarch
is indebted to you.
Any help you need,
we will provide it, hero.
Oh.
I did get separated
from my teacher.
Oh, no, Master Lloyd is lost?
No, it's a...
different teacher.
You wouldn't know him.
Actually, on second thought,
I think I can find him
on my own.
[squeaking]
[Leaf Blade]
If your teacher needs rescue,
then I myself will
accompany you on your quest,
by our Draconic Majesty's
request.
[awkwardly]
Sure. Yeah. Good.
Good...
Down there!
I think I see him!
Huh?
[roaring]
[landing]
Fool.
Weird way to say
"Thanks for the rescue."
Why did you bring
this dragon to me?
I once hunted these creatures
for Imperium.
You don't think
I don't know that?
But they insisted they help.
If they recognize me--
Leaf Blade,
can we check that out?
[Leaf Blade] Of course.
[beeping switch]
Looks like our potential friend
left this behind.
[muttering]
Get rid of the dragon.
Thanks for everything,
Leaf Blade,
but my teacher and I
have to get to the Temple
of the Dragon Cores, and--
The Matriarch
would want me to help you.
I will take you there.
It's like watching
a graceful dance.
Are you seeing this?
Little busy.
If we're gonna fight
Dragonians,
we gotta be able
to fly like them.
I can never operate
at peak efficiency without you.
That is the sweetest thing
you have ever said.
Perhaps, once the threat
from the Forbidden Five
is neutralized--
-Yes.
-But...
I did not ask a question yet.
Were you going to ask
if we could explore
the Merged Lands together?
Affirmative.
My answer is yes.
[beeping]
We have located
the final Prismatic Blade.
[sighing in delight]
They recognized me.
[Arin] Don't be paranoid.
[Leaf Blade]
I will wait for you.
You don't have to do that.
I insist.
Okay, then.
All right, Janus Melons...
[revving engine]
...get ready for the getting.
Whoo-hoo!
Whoa!
[grunting with effort]
[revving engine]
Ha! Impend this destruction.
Hmm.
I suppose your old teacher
told you who that is?
Lloyd's grandpa,
the First Spinjitzu Master.
People say he created Ninjago,
and some of the other realms.
He did, but he's long gone now.
[grunting with effort]
[smashing]
[stone crumbling]
What-what did you do that for?
Spirit of the Temple!
Face me!
[Spirit of the Temple]
Welcome, travelers.
I... The statue!
Spirit,
is there a way to create
Source Dragon Icons
without gathering
Elemental Powers?
There is,
but that knowledge is reserved
for descendants
of the First Spinjitzu Master.
I have this.
A Source Dragon Icon?
Impressive.
Almost as powerful
as a Dragon Core.
Exactly.
[roaring]
Tell me what I need to know!
[groaning in pain]
Oh, please, no!
[gasping]
Ras, stop!
You're hurting him!
-[grunting]
Tell me!
[groaning in pain]
In the depths of the Underworld,
the Casket of Bones...
[groaning]
Forge of the Forgotten!
[shouting in pain]
Most helpful. You may go.
Fie! A pox upon you villains!
[Arin] I'm not a--
Why do you care what name
that spirit calls you?
Villains hurt people.
I don't want to hurt anyone.
Will you do what it takes
to get your parents back?
[sadly] Of course.
[Leaf Blade] There he is!
Is it truly him?
You were foolish
to come among us,
Ras of Imperium.
Did you think your crime
would be forgotten?
Beware, Arin!
The person masquerading
as your teacher
was the leader
of the Claws of the Imperium!
I know. I... I can explain.
[shocked] You knew?
But his soldiers hunted us!
They caged Riyu!
Yeah, but it's... complicated.
No, it is simple.
We will take him
before the Matriarch,
where he will be judged
for his crimes
against Dragon-kind.
[Ras growling]
This doesn't
have to be a fight.
You defend this wretch?
What happened to you,
Arin of the Crossroads?
You have every right
to be angry at Ras,
to have a need for justice,
but I have a need too.
I lost my family in the Merge.
I've sacrificed
everything else in my life
to find them.
I need Ras
if I have any hope
of getting them back.
You say you're indebted to me?
Then let Ras go.
I'm begging you.
No.
It is too much to ask.
We are taking Ras with us.
[Ras growling]
[roaring]
I'm sorry,
Arin of the Crossroads.
So am I.
Running is needless.
I can destroy them!
That's what I'm afraid of.
I think we lost them.
They have a tactical advantage
in the skies.
We must stand and fight.
Not happening.
[distant roaring]
There's something I learned
from being a kid in the streets
that a big guy like you
could never teach me.
What could that possibly be?
How being small...
[slamming]
...can be awesome.
[blasting]
[grunting]
Ridiculous tactics.
[Arin sighs]
You're welcome.
[Wyldfyre] I've got it!
This stew
is going to do wonders!
Old Roby back in no time!
In no time!
A little extra time, maybe?
No change in his vitals.
How could it not work?
You said my logic was perfect!
[Med Bot] That is not what I--
If this isn't the cure,
w-what is?
For many illnesses,
there simply is no cure.
[growling in frustration]
Ugh!
[roaring]
[sighing sadly]
Oh...
This would all be a lot easier
if everyone wasn't always
trying to capture you.
[Ras] I told you.
Strength attracts--
[Arin] --challenge, I know.
Not sure we need
extra challenges right now.
Everyone thinks I'm like you,
a villain.
The Ninja probably think
the same thing.
Who cares what the Ninja think?
Your need to be liked
is a weakness.
Guess it's not like
I'll see any of them
anytime soon.
[vehicle landing nearby]
Arin?
Sora?
[♪♪♪]